Hello and welcome to the AWS certified solutions
Xin chào và chào mừng bạn đến với
architecture associate course.
khóa học AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate.
My name is Stéphane Maarek
Tôi là Stéphane Maarek
and I will be your instructor for this course.
và tôi sẽ là giảng viên hướng dẫn khóa học này.
So I'm delighted to have you here.
Tôi rất vui khi có bạn ở đây.
We're going to start in five minutes
Chúng ta sẽ bắt đầu sau 5 phút
so please pay attention to this lecture.
nên hãy chú ý theo dõi bài giảng này.
So we are going to prepare
Chúng ta sẽ chuẩn bị
for the solutions architect exam of code SAA-C03
cho kỳ thi Solutions Architect mã SAA-C03
and it's a challenging, yet super interesting certification.
- một chứng chỉ khó nhưng rất thú vị.
And this course will cover everything you need to
Khóa học này sẽ bao gồm mọi thứ
know to pass the certification.
bạn cần để vượt qua chứng chỉ.
So this course is long.
Khóa học này khá dài,
It's about 25 hours long
khoảng 25 tiếng,
but I will make sure it's my promise
nhưng tôi hứa với bạn
to you to keep it as interesting as possible along the way.
sẽ làm cho nó thú vị nhất có thể.
You will learn a lot.
Bạn sẽ học được rất nhiều.
I expect you to know some basic things about IT.
Tôi mong bạn có kiến thức IT cơ bản.
Although I will teach you a few things
Dù vậy tôi sẽ dạy bạn một số thứ
along the way and be sure of one thing
trong quá trình và hãy tin chắc rằng
I will teach you everything you need to know about AWS.
tôi sẽ dạy mọi thứ cần biết về AWS.
So this course contain videos from my other courses
Khóa học này có video từ các khóa khác
such as the AWS certified Cloud Practitioner course,
như AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner,
Developer and SysOps course, because there's a shared amount
Developer và SysOps, vì có nhiều
of knowledge between all the AWS courses.
kiến thức chung giữa các khóa AWS.
So if you hear me say some keywords
Nếu nghe tôi nhắc đến từ khóa
or talk about the wrong exam
hoặc nói về kỳ thi khác,
don't worry you are in the right place, nonetheless
đừng lo - bạn vẫn đang ở đúng nơi.
but there is a very exciting query section in this course
Có một phần rất thú vị trong khóa học này,
actually more than one section
thực tế là nhiều phần,
but it's dedicated to solution architecture.
dành riêng cho solution architecture.
And so we will do a deep dive on this in this course.
Chúng ta sẽ tìm hiểu sâu về điều này.
We will cover over 30 AWS services in depth.
Sẽ tìm hiểu hơn 30 dịch vụ AWS chi tiết.
So you will learn a lot
Bạn sẽ học được rất nhiều.
And finally, if you're a beginner in AWS
Cuối cùng, nếu bạn mới bắt đầu với AWS
you are more than welcome.
thì rất được chào đón.
Just take your time with this course.
Hãy từ từ với khóa học này.
It's not a race and if you need to revisit
Đây không phải cuộc đua, nếu cần
the course a second time
xem lại khóa học lần thứ hai
or revisit some videos, it is okay.
hoặc xem lại video thì cũng bình thường.
Many students have to do it
Nhiều học viên phải làm vậy
before mastering all the concepts.
trước khi nắm vững hết khái niệm.
So why should I teach this course to you?
Tại sao tôi nên dạy khóa học này?
Well, I just passed the SAA-C03 exam
Tôi vừa vượt qua kỳ thi SAA-C03
with the score of 96.1%.
với điểm 96.1%.
That's even before following my new topics at the exam.
Thậm chí trước khi tôi cập nhật nội dung mới.
So hopefully I'm the right teacher for you.
Hy vọng tôi là giảng viên phù hợp.
I also hold nine other AWS certifications.
Tôi cũng có 9 chứng chỉ AWS khác.
So, I've taught AWS to a few people now, already.
Tôi đã dạy AWS cho khá nhiều người rồi.
So, who am I?
Tôi là ai?
Well for those who don't know me, my name is Stéphane Maarek
Với ai chưa biết, tôi là Stéphane Maarek
and I've been teaching AWS certifications
và đã dạy chứng chỉ AWS
to hundreds of thousands of students around the world.
cho hàng trăm nghìn học viên toàn thế giới.
So, I used to work as an IT consultant
Tôi từng làm IT consultant
and as an AWS solutions architect, Developer and SysOps.
và AWS Solutions Architect, Developer, SysOps.
So I'm quite familiar with AWS
Nên khá quen với AWS
and I've also built websites, applications
và cũng đã xây dựng website, ứng dụng
and streaming platforms on the cloud.
và nền tảng streaming trên cloud.
I'm a veteran instructor on AWS.
Tôi là giảng viên AWS kỳ cựu,
I've teach about 10 certifications.
dạy khoảng 10 chứng chỉ.
I teach about CloudFormation, Lambda, and EC2
Dạy về CloudFormation, Lambda, EC2
and obviously solutions architect associate.
và tất nhiên Solutions Architect Associate.
You can find me on various platforms on GitHub.
Bạn có thể tìm tôi trên GitHub,
You can follow me on LinkedIn.
follow trên LinkedIn,
You can read about me on Medium and follow me on Twitter.
đọc trên Medium và follow Twitter.
If you want to connect with me.
Nếu muốn kết nối với tôi.
So very shortly, we'll have a lot more deep dive
Nói ngắn gọn, chúng ta sẽ tìm hiểu sâu
onto what's AWS, but AWS stands for Amazon web services
AWS là gì, nhưng AWS - Amazon Web Services
and it is a cloud provider.
là một cloud provider.
It provides you with servers and services that you can use
Cung cấp server và dịch vụ bạn có thể dùng
on demand and scale easily, which is a big, big difference
theo yêu cầu và mở rộng dễ dàng -
from what you used to do on premises in your data center
khác biệt lớn so với on-premises trong data center
where you had to order your servers physically
nơi bạn phải đặt mua server vật lý
and install them before being able to use them.
rồi cài đặt mới dùng được.
On the cloud, we can get them whenever we want so on demand
Trên cloud, có được ngay khi cần
and we can have as many as we want so we can scale easily.
và muốn bao nhiêu cũng được - dễ mở rộng.
And thanks to AWS as it has been revolutionized.
AWS đã cách mạng hóa điều này.
And now today, AWS power some
Hiện AWS cung cấp sức mạnh cho
of the biggest websites in the world.
các website lớn nhất thế giới.
So you will be surprised
Bạn sẽ không ngạc nhiên
not surprised about amazon.com obviously because well
về amazon.com vì AWS thuộc Amazon,
AWS belongs to Amazon, but for Netflix
nhưng với Netflix -
they actually don't own a single server.
họ không sở hữu một server nào.
They rent everything from AWS
Thuê toàn bộ từ AWS
which allows Netflix to run at scale.
giúp Netflix vận hành quy mô lớn.
So, what are we going to learn in this course? Well,
Chúng ta sẽ học gì trong khóa này?
we're going to learn a lot of AWS services.
Sẽ học rất nhiều dịch vụ AWS.
As you can see some of them are right here.
Như bạn thấy một số ở đây,
There's even more, but I didn't wanna show them.
còn nhiều hơn nhưng tôi không hiện hết.
So don't feel overwhelmed.
Đừng cảm thấy choáng ngợp.
My goal is to teach, show to you one by one.
Mục tiêu là dạy từng cái một.
So I like to say that AWS is a spaghetti bowl
Tôi hay nói AWS như bát mì ống
because all these services are linked
vì tất cả dịch vụ này liên kết
and interconnected with one another.
và kết nối với nhau.
But with me we're going to entangle
Nhưng cùng tôi chúng ta sẽ gỡ rối
this entire spaghetti bowl,
toàn bộ bát mì này,
have a very good meal, and learn AWS together.
có bữa ăn ngon và học AWS cùng nhau.
So I hope you're excited.
Hy vọng bạn hào hứng.
I'm definitely excited to teach this course
Tôi chắc chắn hào hứng dạy khóa này
to you and I will see you in the next lecture.
và sẽ gặp bạn trong bài giảng sau.